A Guide to the Henry H. Douglas Collection, 1861-1978
Virginia Room, Fairfax County Public Library
- Series 2: Negatives
  - Sub-series 2-2: Echoes of History, 1968-1976
    - W&OD Railroad Crossing the Alexandria Canal / Alexandria Canal and the Herbert Bryant Fertilizer Plant (v.3, no.1, p.6 [2 negatives]), 1970 (Box 2)
    - Carlyle House (v.3, no.1, p.11), 1971 (Box 2)
    - Green's Mansion House - Mansion House General Hospital, later Carlyle Apartments (v.3, no.1, p.12), Undated (Box 2)
    - General Mills Granary (1971) / Steam Train no. 121 of Southern Railway pulling into Round Hill circa 1908 (v.3, no.1, p.13 [ 2 negatives]), 1971 (Box 2)
    - Colvin Run Barn (1969) / Sterling Emporium Company Store (n.d) (v.3, no.1, p.14 [ 2 negatives]), 1969 (Box 2)
    - Fry/Dosh House and Anderson House (1973) (v.3, no.1, p.15), 1973 January 28 (Box 2)
    - Fry/Dosh House (1973) / Carlyle Apartments in 1971 (v.3, no.1, p.16 [2 negatives]), 1971; 1973 (Box 2)
    - Barn at Little Sully in 1971 / Barn Posts at Little Sully in 1973 (v.3, no.2, p.17 [2 negatives]), Undated (Box 2)
    - Alexander Haight at Little Sully (v.3, no.2, p.19), Undated (Box 2)
    - Remains of Basement and Barns at Little Sully (1971) / Home of A.B. Stanley, 11213 Lee Highway, Fairfax (v.3, no.2, p.20 [2 negatives]), 1971 (Box 2)
    - Tourist Cabins Built by the Winfield Family (v.3, no.2, p.21), Undated (Box 2)
    - Stonewall Mill about 1920 (v.3, no.2, p.22), Undated (Box 2)
    - Stonewall Mill Dam on the Shenandoah River in the 1930s / Reverend Lawson Turner Thompson in the 1880s (v.3, no.2, p.23), Undated (Box 2)
    - Gravestone for Armistead T. Thompson, Thompson Cemetery / Tobin Gravestone, Thompson Cemetery (v.3, no.2, p.24), Undated (Box 2)
    - The "Dairy" at Mt. Air, 9101 Lee Highway / Rita (Thompson) Covington and Florence (Bray) Stevens at Hatmark School, 9333 Lee Highway / Map of Cockpit Point (v.3, no.2, p.25 [3 negatives]), Undated (Box 2)
    - Sketch of Cockpit Point Battery from 1862 / Ship's Lantern found on Possum Nose / Possum Nose from Cockpit Point (1972) (v.3, no.2, p.26 [3 negatives]), 1972 (Box 2)
    - Possum Nose (1972) / Shell Fragment at Cockpit Point (1972) / Bolt from Whitworth Gun Fired at Cockpit Point Battery (v.3, no.2, p.27 [3 negatives]), 1972 (Box 2)
    - Goose Creek W&OD Bridge (v.3, no.2, p.29), 1969 (Box 2)
    - Bridge over Four Mile Run at Little Falls Road (v.3, no.2, p.30), 1968 (Box 2)
    - Paul Sager Barn behind 10450 Lee Highway (v.3, no.2, p.31), 1972 (Box 2)
    - Swart Farm Buildings in July 1968 (v.3, no.2, p.32), Undated (Box 2)
    - Remains of the Wharf at Aquia Creek Landing (v.3, no.3, p.33), Undated (Box 2)
    - "Beanpole and Cornstalk" Bridge across Potomac Creek (v.3, no.3, p.35), Undated (Box 2)
    - Virginia Route 608 to Aquia Landing (1972) / Remains of an Abutment for Bridge over Potomac Creek (1972) (v.3, no.3, p.36 [2 negatives]), 1972 (Box 2)
    - Brig. General Herman Haupt / Major General Joseph Hooker's Supply Base at Aquia Creek Landing in 1863 (v.3, no.3, p.37 [2 negatives]), Undated (Box 2)
    - Oak Tree at 2911 Hunter Mill Road, Oakton (v.3, no.3, p.39), 1973 (Box 2)
    - Mounting Block near Ayre House / Ayre House (1973) (v.3, no.3, p.41 [2 negatives]), Undated (Box 2)
    - Alexander Haight Examining Hitching Block / Arthur Wrenn House / Watering Dish and Spring House at Arthur Wrenn House (v.3, no.3, p.42 [3 negatives]), Undated (Box 2)
    - Downs Store on Route 50 about 1945 / Chantilly Baptist Church (v.3, no.3, p.43), Undated (Box 2)
    - "The Hermitage" (Philip DeCatesby Jones Lee House) in 1973 (v.3, no.3, p.44), Undated (Box 2)
    - Steps of Christ Episcopal Church, Chantilly / Christ Church Graveyard, Chantilly (1973) / Alexander Haight at his Aunt's Grave (v.3, no.3, p.45 [3 negatives]), 1973 (Box 2)
    - "Tuckaway," Home of Abner and Sam Wrenn / Cain Branch, West of Rt. 657 (v.3, no.3, p.46 [2 negatives]), Undated (Box 2)
    - Christ Episcopal Church, Chantilly (1963) / Christ Episcopal Church (v.3, no.3, p.48 [2 negatives]), Undated (Box 2)
    - Beverly Mill in 1946 (v. 3, no. 4, p. 49) / on Fairfax and Prince William County line, Undated (Box 2)
    - River Barges, Aquia Creek, 1862-63 (v. 3, no. 4, p. 51), Undated (Box 2)
    - Rebel Steamer "Page" at Aquia Creek (ca. 1861) (v. 3, no. 4, p. 52), Undated (Box 2)
    - Aquia Creek, June 1863 (v. 3, no. 4, p. 52), Undated (Box 2)
    - Aquia Landing, July 1973 (v. 3, no. 4, p. 52) / at low tide, 1973 July (Box 2)
    - Potomac Creek Bridge, second on the site (v. 3, no. 4, p. 53) / called by Lincoln as made of "beanpoles and cornstalks", Undated (Box 2)
    - Aquia Landing, brick foundations, July 1973 (v. 3, no. 4, p, 53), 1973 July (Box 2)
    - Potomac Creek Bridge (modern), July 1973 (v. 3, no. 4, p. 54), 1973 July (Box 2)
    - Rapidan Dam Canal, Lock #7, March 1968 (v. 3, no. 4, p. 56/57) / part of Rappahannock Navigation, 1968 March (Box 2)
    - Tyro Mill inner workings, Tyro, VA (v. 3, no. 4, p. 59), Undated (Box 2)
    - Mountain Cabin, built ca. 1890 (v. 3, no. 4, p. 59), Undated (Box 2)
    - McAtee Oak, at Chain Bridge and Jermantown Roads, Oakton, VA, June 1973 (v. 3, no. 4., p. 63), 1973 June (Box 2)
    - Broad Run Bridge Destruction due to Hurricane Agnes, April 1973 (v. 3, no. 5, p. 65) / located on Leesburg Pike 9 miles southeast of Leesburg, 1973 April (Box 2)
    - Halfway House, 1895 (v. 3, no. 5, p. 68) / "halfway between Lexington and Alexandria", Undated (Box 2)
    - Valley Pike Stagecoach, last run between Staunton and Winchester in 1874 (v. 3, no. 5, p. 69), Undated (Box 2)
    - Painter Family, Threshing with steam engine ca. 1894 (v. 3, no. 5, p. 70), Undated (Box 2)
    - Old Stone House, 3051 M St. NW, Georgetown, 1973 (v. 3, no. 5, p. 75), Undated (Box 2)
    - Ewell's Chapel, 1973 (v. 3, no. 5, p. 76), 1973 (Box 2)
    - Jerusalem Baptist Church on site of Payne's Chapel, 1968 (v. 3, no. 5, p. 77), 1968 July (Box 2)
    - Mt. Zion Episcopal Church, located half way between Chain Bridge Road and Truro Episcopal Church (v. 3, no. 5, p. 77), Undated (Box 2)
    - Duncan Chapel being torn down, 19 Jan 1970 (v. 3, no. 5, p. 78), 1970 January 19 (Box 2)
    - Duncan Chapel being torn down, 19 Jan 1970 (v. 3, no. 5, p. 78) / Inner support visible, 1970 January 19 (Box 2)
    - Kincheloe House, on Lee Highway close to Rte. 236 (v. 3, no. 5, p. 79), 1970 April 29 (Box 2)
    - Bacon's Castle, rear view (v. 3, no. 5, p. 80), Undated (Box 2)
    - Buckland Tavern, 1971 (v. 3, no. 6, p. 81) west of Gainesville, on Broad Run (v. 3, no. 5, p. 81), Undated (Box 2)
    - Buckland Map, Prince William County (v. 3, no. 6, p. 83), Undated (Box 2)
    - St. Mark's Methodist Church, built 1854 (v. 3, no. 6, p. 84) (in Buckland), 1971 May (Box 2)
    - Leitch House, aka "Deerlick", September 1973 (v. 3, no. 6, p. 85) / once site of a noted still, 1973 September (Box 2)
    - Door of Leitch House, pockmarked with nail holes, September 1973 (v. 3, no. 6, p. 85) / holes due to posted notices when building served as general store, bar and post office, 1973 September (Box 2)
    - Old Grist Mill, September 1973 (v. 3, no. 6, p. 86) / in Buckland on Mill Street, 1973 September (Box 2)
    - Fred Painter at the Fry-Dosh House in Woodstock, VA, February 1973 (v. 3, no. 6, p. 87), 1973 February (Box 2)
    - Views of Road Construction, eastern Tennessee (v.3, no. 6, p. 88) (2 negatives), 1973 September (Box 2)
    - Painter Graves in community cemetery, 8 July 1973 (v. 3, no. 6, p. 89), 1973 July 8 (Box 2)
    - Woodstock, scene of largest steam engine in Shenandoah County, ca. 1906 (v. 3, no. 6, p. 90), Undated (Box 2)
    - Barrett Barn, north of Sudley Road, Manassas, built 1932, photo 1972 (v. 3, no. 6, p. 91) / "unusually fine stone construction", 1972 (Box 2)
    - Ben Lomond Barn, north of Sudley Road, Manassas, 1971 (v. 3, no. 6, p. 91), 1971 May (Box 2)
    - Hooper Island Lighthouse, south of Cambridge, MD (v. 3, no. 6, p. 92), Undated (Box 2)
    - Marlborough Town, archeological excavation on Potomac River, Stafford County, 1956 (v. 3, no. 6, p. 94), Undated (Box 2)
    - Rappahannock Canal, wooden rail possible remnant of canal boat, 1973 (v. 3, no. 6, p. 96), 1973 (Box 2)
    - Rappahannock Canal, remnants of locks, 1973 (v. 3, no. 6, p. 96), 1973 (Box 2)
    - Rappahannock Canal, remnant of head lock opposite Deep Run, 1973 (v. 3, no. 6, p. 96), 1973 (Box 2)
    - Rappahannock Canal, tie iron set into stone, 1973 (v. 3, no. 6, p. 96), 1973 (Box 2)
    - Rappahannock Canal, stone cutter's mark, 1973 (v. 3, no. 6, p. 96), 1973 (Box 2)
    - Catoctin Furnace, near Frederick, MD, December 1972 (v. 4, no. 1, p. 1), 1972 December (Box 2)
    - Open Mine near Catoctin Furnace, ca. 1895 (v. 4, no. 1, p. 4), Undated (Box 2)
    - Catoctin Furnace map, May 1970 (v. 4, no. 1, p. 5), 1970 May (Box 2)
    - Mine Bank at Blue Mountain, ca. 1900 (v. 4, no. 1, p. 6), Undated (Box 2)
    - Ironmaster's House, built 1774, photo 1948 (v. 4, no. 1, p. 6), Undated (Box 2)
    - Catoctin Furnace, ca. 1900 (v. 4, no. 1, p. 7), Undated (Box 2)
    - Catoctin Furnace complex, ca. 1900 (v. 4, no. 1, p. 7), Undated (Box 2)
    - The Herald Building, 10400 Main St., Fairfax (v. 4, no. 1, p. 8), Undated (Box 2)
    - The Herald Press Room, ca. 1967 (v. 4, no. 1, p. 9), Undated (Box 2)
    - The Herald Press Room rear corner, ca. 1967 (v. 4, no. 1, p. 9), Undated (Box 2)
    - The Herald front office, ca. 1967 (v. 4, no. 1, p. 10), Undated (Box 2)
    - The Herald front office, ca. 1967 (v. 4, no. 1, p. 10), Undated (Box 2)
    - The Herald front office, ca. 1967 (v. 4, no. 1, p. 11), Undated (Box 2)
    - Reed and Money, Undertakers and Embalmers ad 23 February 1917 (v. 4, no. 1, p. 11), Undated (Box 2)
    - Carne House, 3708 Chain Bridge Road, 1971 (v. 4, no. 1, p. 11), 1971 (Box 2)
    - Carne House, 3708 Chain Bridge Road, 1971 (v. 4, no. 1, p. 12), 1971 (Box 2)
    - Carne House, 3708 Chain Bridge Road, 1971 (v. 4, no. 1, p. 12), 1971 (Box 2)
    - Confederate earthworks ca. 1861, Freestone Point, south of Occoquan River in Prince William County, 1972 (v. 4, no. 1, p. 13), 1972 (Box 2)
    - U.S.S. Jacob Bell, part of Potomac Flotilla (v. 4, no. 1, p. 14), Undated (Box 2)
    - Remains of house of Henry Fairfax, 1972 (v. 4, no. 1, p. 14) / on Leesylvania tract, 1972 (Box 2)
    - Cemetery of Henry Lee and Lucy Grymes, 1972 (v. 4, no. 1., p. 14), 1972 (Box 2)
    - Catoctin Furnace complex, 20 April 1974 (v. 4, no. 2, p. 17), 1974 April 20 (Box 2)
    - Grace Bear on her homestead (v. 4, no. 2., p, 19), Undated (Box 2)
    - Grace Bear's home in the forest (v. 4, no. 2, p. 19), Undated (Box 2)
    - Coos County, OR, spruce trees being lumbered (v. 4, no. 2, p. 19), Undated (Box 2)
    - Hyatt Manor, 1410 Rhode Island Ave., Hyattsville, ca. 1940's (v. 4, no. 2, p. 20), Undated (Box 2)
    - Grace Bear in her Buick Roadster at Hyatt Manor, 1942 (v. 4, no. 2, p. 20), Undated (Box 2)
    - Buckland Manor, front, 1944 (v. 4, no. 2, p. 21), Undated (Box 2)
    - Buckland Manor, rear, ca. 1940's (v. 4, no. 2, p. 21), Undated (Box 2)
    - Buckland Hall, after restoration, ca. 1950's (v. 4, no. 2, p. 21), Undated (Box 2)
    - Grace Bear, possible interior of solarium (v. 4, no. 2, p. 22), Undated (Box 2)
    - Buckland Tavern, March 1970 (v. 4, no. 2, p. 22) / when Mrs. Bear went to nursing home, 1970 March (Box 2)
    - Buckland Tavern, August 1973 (v. 4, no. 2, p. 23) / when "jungle" took over, 1973 August (Box 2)
    - Catoctin Village, iron worker's cottage, 20 April 1974 (v. 4, no. 2, p. 24), 1974 April 20 (Box 2)
    - Catoctin Village, iron worker's cottage (v. 4, no. 2, p. 24), Undated (Box 2)
    - Catoctin Village, iron worker's cottage (v. 4, no. 2, p. 24), Undated (Box 2)
    - Catoctin, Baker Johnson House, built 1805 (v. 4, no. 2, p. 25), Undated (Box 2)
    - Catoctin, Windy Hill, built 1805, photo 24 April 1974 (v. 4, no. 2, p. 25), 1974 April 24 (Box 2)
    - Catoctin Village, interior walls furnace master's house, 20 April 1974 (v. 4, no. 2, p. 25), 1974 April 20 (Box 2)
    - Sully, 23 May 1971 (v. 4, no. 2, p. 26), 1971 May 23 (Box 2)
    - Lawn of Sully, 21 April 1973 (v. 4, no. 2, p. 27), 1973 April 21 (Box 2)
    - Langley Tavern in 1921 (v. 4, no. 2, p. 27), Undated (Box 2)
    - Langley Tavern, drawing by John Linton (v. 4, no. 2, p. 28), Undated (Box 2)
    - Spring House (v. 4, no. 2, p. 32), Undated (Box 2)
    - Tidewater Indian village drawing (v. 4, no. 3, p. 33), Undated (Box 2)
    - Council of Powhatan drawing by John Smith (v. 4, no. 3, p. 35), Undated (Box 2)
    - Tools of Planters of Jamestown (v. 4, no. 3, p. 36), Undated (Box 2)
    - Haymarket, E. Main St., ca. 1900 (v. 4, no. 3, p. 37), Undated (Box 2)
    - Haymarket, Post Office, ca. 1900 (v. 4, no. 3, p. 38), Undated (Box 2)
    - Haymarket, Dr. Henry Mazyck Clarkson home, ca. 1900 (v. 4, no. 3, p. 38), Undated (Box 2)
    - Haymarket, Town Hall, ca. 1974 (v. 4, no. 3, p. 39), ca 1974 (Box 2)
    - Haymarket, Town Hall, ca. 1900 (v. 4, no. 3, p. 39), Undated (Box 2)
    - Haymarket, Red House, June 1974 (v. 4, no. 3, p. 40) / at the intersection of Washington and Jefferson Streets, 1974 June (Box 2)
    - Haymarket, St. Paul's Episcopal Church, c 1800-05, photo 1973 (v. 4, no. 3, p. 40) / building designed by James Wren, 1973 (Box 2)
    - Alice Fellows, 1971 (v. 4, no. 3, p. 41), 1971 (Box 2)
    - Charles D. Price, Jr., 7 July 1970 (v. 4, no. 3, p. 42), 1970 July 7 (Box 2)
    - Shiefferstadt, Frederick, MD, built ca. 1736 (v. 4, no. 3, p. 45) / corner of Rosemount Ave. and West 2nd St., Undated (Box 2)
    - "Tin-Tin" John aka Wendelin Masarik (v. 4, no. 3, p. 46), Undated (Box 2)
    - "Tin-Tin" John aka Wendelin Masarik, 18 Oct 1973 (v. 4, no. 3, p. 46), 1973 October 18 (Box 2)
    - Gaithersburg, Maryland, B&O-C&O depot (v. 4, no. 4, p. 52), Undated (Box 2)
    - Manassas, Virginia, Southern Railway depot (v. 4, no. 4, p. 52), Undated (Box 2)
    - The Arcade, part of Madison House Tavern, ca 1904 (v.4, no. 4, p. 53), Undated (Box 2)
    - Dumfries historical marker, Sept 1974 (v. 4, no. 4, p. 55), 1974 September (Box 2)
    - Israel Folsom grave marker 1772, probably oldest stone in Quantico Cemetery, photo Sept 1974 (v. 4, no. 4, p. 55), 1974 September (Box 2)
    - Quantico Cemetery, Dumfries, Virginia, Sept 1974 (v. 4, no. 4, p. 55), 1974 September (Box 2)
    - Colonial Dumfries artifacts, Sept 1974, 1974 September (Box 2)
    - William's Ordinary, ca. 1760, Dumfries, photo 1969 (v. 4, no. 4, p. 56), 1969 (Box 2)
    - Walker Mill, Albemarle County, 1783, photo 1972 (v. 4, no. 4, p. 59), 1972 (Box 2)
    - Merrie Mill, Albemarle County, ca. 1735, built for Col. John Walker of "Belvoir", photo 1972 (v. 4, no. 4, p. 59), 1972 (Box 2)
    - Jefferson Mill, near Scottsville, Albemarle County, owned and operated by Peter Field Jefferson, nephew of Thomas Jefferson, photo 1972 (v. 4, no. 4, p. 59), 1972 (Box 2)
    - A.J. Long's Mill, Greene County, measured drawing (v. 4, no. 4, p. 61), Undated (Box 2)
    - A.J. Long's Mill, Lynch River, Greene County, photo (v. 4, no. 4, p. 61), Undated (Box 2)
    - Repton Mill, Madison County, photo 1971 (v. 4, no. 4, p. 62), 1971 (Box 2)
    - Graves' Mill, Madison County, photo 1971 (v. 4, no. 4, p. 62), 1971 (Box 2)
    - Variety Mill, east of Arrington, Nelson County, photo 1973 (v. 4, no. 4, p. 62), 1973 (Box 2)
    - Woodson's Mill, Nelson County, near Lowesville, photo 1971 (v. 4, no. 4, p. 63), 1971 (Box 2)
    - Midway Mill, Nelson County, near Wingina, photo May 1969 (v. 4, no. 4, p. 64), 1969 May (Box 2)
    - Midway Mill millhouse, Nelson County, near Wingina, photo May 1969 (v. 4, no. 4, p. 64), 1969 May (Box 2)
    - Construction of Georgetown Aqueduct, drawing, ca. 1830's (v. 4, no. 5, p. 65), Undated (Box 2)
    - Taylorstown Mill, Catoctin Valley, Virginia, ca. 1730's (v. 4, no. 5, p. 66), Undated (Box 2)
    - Conrad Virts' house, Catoctin Valley, Virginia (v. 4, no. 5, p. 67), Undated (Box 2)
    - John S. Hutchison house, Catoctin Valley, Virginia, between Waterford and Milltown, built ca. 1820's (v. 4, no. 5, p. 67), Undated (Box 2)
    - Clover Hill, Catoctin Valley, Virginia, built ca. 1750's (v. 4, no. 5, p. 67), Undated (Box 2)
    - Footloose, Catoctin Valley, Virginia, Route 665 two miles north of Taylorstown (v. 4, no. 5, p. 68), Undated (Box 2)
    - Hunting Hill, Loudoun County, Virginia, ca. 1734 (v. 4, no. 5, p. 68), Undated (Box 2)
    - Catoctin Mill Farm, Catoctin Valley, Virginia, Route 663 (v. 4, no. 5, p. 68), Undated (Box 2)
    - Tenant House, Catoctin Mill Farm (v. 4, no. 5, p. 69), Undated (Box 2)
    - Foxton Cottage, Catoctin Valley, Virginia (v. 4, no. 5, p. 69), 1974 (Box 2)
    - Foxton Cottage, head of the stairs (v. 4, no. 5, p. 70), 1974 (Box 2)
    - Foxton Cottage, original ground floor room (v. 4, no. 5, p. 71), 1974 (Box 2)
    - Graphic depiction of construction of pier inside a coffer dam (v. 4, no. 5, p. 72), Undated (Box 2)
    - Stylized rendering of proposed Alexandria Canal Park (v. 4, no. 5, p. 73), Undated (Box 2)
    - Plan of locality of proposed Alexandria Canal Park (v. 4, no. 5, 73), Undated (Box 2)
    - General Matthew Calbraith Butler and staff at Camp Alger Headquarters, 1898-1899 (v. 4, no. 5, p. 74), Undated (Box 2)
    - House, facing Camp Alger headquarters, destroyed 1962 (v. 4, no. 5, p. 74), Undated (Box 2)
    - Sudley Mill, Sudley Spring, Prince William County, as it appeared during the Civil War (v. 4, no. 5, p. 75), Undated (Box 2)
    - Sudley Mill, Sudley Spring, Prince William County, circa 1931 (v. 4, no. 5, p. 76), Undated (Box 2)
    - Map of Sudley area, Prince William County (v. 4, no. 5, p. 76), Undated (Box 2)
    - Sudley Post Office outhouse (v. 4, no. 5, p. 77), 1974 November (Box 2)
    - Sudley Post Office (v. 4, no. 5, p. 77), 1974 November (Box 2)
    - Map of Sudley area, Prince William County (v. 4, no. 5, p. 77), Undated (Box 2)
    - Sudley Mill in the 1890s(?) (v. 4, no. 5, p. 77), Undated (Box 2)
    - Boggess house, Old Colchester Road (v. 4, no. 5, p. 79), Undated (Box 2)
    - Bard House, Main Street, Slippery Rock, Pa. (v. 4, no. 6, p. 84), Undated (Box 2)
    - Jimmy Kerr House, Slippery Rock, Pa. (v. 4, no. 6, p. 84), Undated (Box 2)
    - Mrs. An I Hilgar and Ronald Meshanko during interview (v. 4, no. 6, p. 85), Undated (Box 2)
    - Left: (Covert) Patterson House; Right: J. Mayburry House, Slippery Rock, Pa. (v. 4, no. 6, p. 85), Undated (Box 2)
    - McCoy House, Slippery Rock, Pa. (v. 4, no. 6, p. 86), Undated (Box 2)
    - Former Dowl Kiester Mortuary, Slippery Rock, Pa. (v. 4, no. 6, p. 86), Undated (Box 2)
    - Henry Hilger's (Hilgar's) Donation Grant Deed for Revolutionary War Service, 1786 (v. 4, no. 6, p. 86), Undated (Box 2)
    - Mr. and Mrs. Ollie H. Hilgar holding Hilgar Donation Grant Deed (v. 4, no. 6, p. 86), Undated (Box 2)
    - Dowl Kiester House, Main Street, Slippery Rock, Pa. (v. 4, no. 6, p. 87), Undated (Box 2)
    - South side of McConnell's Mill, Slippery Rock Creek, Pa. (v. 4, no. 6, p. 90), Undated (Box 2)
    - McConnell's Mill (looking northeast), Slippery Rock Creek, Pa. (v. 4, no. 6, p. 90), Undated (Box 2)
    - Original machinery inside McConnell's Mill, Slippery Rock Creek, Pa. (v. 4, no. 6, p. 90), Undated (Box 2)
    - Original machinery inside McConnell's Mill, Slippery Rock Creek, Pa. (v. 4, no. 6, p. 90), Undated (Box 2)
    - Fox Mansion (backside), Foxburg, Clarion County, Pa. (v. 4, no. 6, p. 91), Undated (Box 2)
    - Large barn close to Fox Mansion, Foxburg, Clarion County, Pa. (v. 4, no. 6, p. 91), Undated (Box 2)
    - Foltz mill site, Jennings Nature Reserve, Pa. 9V. 4, no. 6, p. 92), Undated (Box 2)
    - Side view of large barn close to Fox Mansion, Foxburg, Clarion County, Pa. (v. 4, no. 6, p. 92), Undated (Box 2)
    - Rear entrance to Fox Mansion, Foxburg, Clarion County, Pa. (v. 4, no. 6, p. 92), Undated (Box 2)
    - Sandstone wall at Foltz mill site, Jennings Nature Reserve, Pa. (v. 4, no. 6, p. 94), Undated (Box 2)
    - William D. Wicks grave marker, Slippery Rock Cemetery, Pa. (v. 4, no. 6, p. 94), 1974 (Box 2)
    - Michael Christley grave marker, Slippery Rock Cemetery, Pa. (v. 4, no. 6, p. 95), 1974 (Box 2)
    - Thos. J. Miller grave marker, Slippery Rock Cemetery, Pa. (v. 4, no. 6, p. 95), 1974 (Box 2)
    - Joseph Donaghy grave marker, Slippery Rock Cemetery, Pa. (v. 4, no 6, p. 95), 1974 (Box 2)
    - Catherine M. Hodge grave marker, Slippery Rock Cemetery, Pa. (v. 4, no. 6, p. 95), 1974 (Box 2)
    - Dr. G. W. Coulter grave marker, Slippery Rock Cemetery, Pa. (v. 4, no. 6, p. 96), 1974 (Box 2)
    - Lovena Uber grave marker, wife of Peter Uber, Slippery Rock Cemetery, Pa. (v. 4, no. 6, p. 96), 1974 (Box 2)
    - Mary Porter, wife of David M. Porter, grave marker, Slippery Rock Cemetery, Pa. (v. 4, no. 6, p. 96), 1974 (Box 2)
    - The Old Slippery Rock Cemetery, Pa. (v. 4, no. 6, p. 96), 1974 (Box 2)
    - Camp Wolf Run Shoals, Winter 1862-3 (v. 5, no. 1, p. 1), Undated (Box 2)
    - Mary and Bill Barrett examine fort near Centreville/Drawing of outbuilding by Fred Bartlett (v. 5 no. 1, p. 2 [2 negatives]), 1975 January (Box 2)
    - Fitzhugh House, 3546 Devon Dr./Map of boundaries of Fitzhugh tract (v. 5, no. 1, p. 3[2 negatives]), 1974 (Box 2)
    - Fitzhugh House, /basement stone walls/ 1834 date and initials "M.C." inscribed in stone wall (v. 5, no. 1, p. 4[2 negatives]), 1974 (Box 2)
    - W&OD Bike Trail in Falls Church, 1974 (Box 2)
    - McCormick House, Haymarket, VA exterior/ interior (v. 5, no. 1, p. 7 [2 negatives]), 1973, 1974 (Box 2)
    - Camp Wolf Run Shoals, Co. A Vermont Volunteers, 1863/Stockade Tents 12th Regiment Vermont Volunteers (v. 5, no. 1, p. 8 [2 negatives]), Undated (Box 2)
    - Truro Rectory, formerly home of Wm. Presley Gunnell, built 1830/ Fords Old Mill, Wolf Run Shoals 1862 (v. 5, no. 1, p. 9 [2 negatives]), Undated (Box 2)
    - Mary E. Wilcoxon home, near Camp Wolf Run Shoals/ Mary E. Wilxocon photo (v. 5, no. 1, p. 10 [2 negatives]), Undated (Box 2)
    - Diagrams of "lizards" devices for hauling (v. 5, no. 1, p 11), Undated (Box 2)
    - Fairfax Arms, Colchester, Va. (v. 5, no. 1, p. 12), Undated (Box 2)
    - Plan of Colchester Town (v. 5, no. 1, p. 14 [2 negatives]), Undated (Box 2)
    - Trickett's, Colvin Run Road (v. 5, no. 1, p. 15), Undated (Box 2)
    - Rockledge, Occoquan, Va. / The Arcade, Madison, Va. (v. 5, no. 1, p. 16 [2 negatives]), Undated (Box 2)
    - Manassas Gap Railroad roadbed images (v. 5, no. 2, p. 17 [2 negatives]), 1972 January (Box 2)
    - Beverly Mill, Cripple Creek, Wythe Co., Va. (v. 5, no. 2, p. 20), Undated (Box 2)
    - Cedar Run Furnace images, Wythe Co., Va. (v. 5, no. 2, p. 21 [2 negatives]), Undated (Box 2)
    - Cedar Run Furnace, Wythe Co., Va./Harkrader-Slater-Musser Mill,, Wythe Co., Va. (v. 5, no. 2, p. 22 [2 negatives]), Undated (Box 2)
    - Speedwell Furnace, Wythe Co., Va. (v. 5, no. 2, p. 23), Undated (Box 2)
    - Manassas Gap Railroad roadbed image/ Stone culvert under roadbed (v. 5, no. 2, p. 24 [2 negatives]), 1972 January (Box 2)
    - Second Grace Episcopal Church, Silver Spring, Md./ Map drawing of location of Grace Episcopal Church 1895/ Invasion of Md. 1864 9 (v. 5, no. 2, p. 26 [3 negatives]), Undated (Box 2)
    - Jubal Early/Stained glass images in Grace Episcopal Church (v. 5, no. 2, p. 27 [3 negatives]), Undated (Box 2)
    - Third Grace Episcopal Church, Silver Spring, Md./ Confederate Memorial 9v. 5, no. 2, p. 28 [2 negatives]), 1974 (Box 2)
    - Parson Weems House, Dumfries, Va./ Weems-Botts House (v. 5, no. 2, p. 29 [2 negatives]), 1974 (Box 2)
    - Seneca Quarry stone mill on the C&O Canal, Montgomery Co., Md. (v. 5, no. 2, p. 30), 1975 (Box 2)
    - Seneca Quarry Master's House, Montgomery Co., Md. (v. 5, no. 2, p. 31), 1975 (Box 2)